

Anuraj Mohan

Academician . Researcher

- Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering
- NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad
- Kerala, India 678008

Education

Doctor of Philosophy

Area : Network Representation Learning

Dept. of Computer Applications

Cochin University of Science and Technology

2017 - 2022

Master of Engineering

Computer Science and Engineering

Anna University, Chennai

2013 - 2015

Bachelor of Technology

Computer Science and Engineering

Cochin University of Science and Technology

2001 - 2005

Biography

Dr. Anuraj Mohan obtained the B.Tech Degree in Computer Science and Engineering from Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin and the Master Degree in Computer Science and Engineering from Anna University, Chennai. He received the Ph.D. degree in the area of network representation learning under the Faculty of Technology, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin. He has more than 18 years of experience as Faculty at Department of Computer Science and Engineering, NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad. He has published various research articles in SCI indexed journals of reputed publishers like Elsevier and Springer. His broad areas of interest include machine learning, text and social network mining, and big data analytics.

Work Experience

Associate Professor Department of Computer Science and Engineering

22/01/2022 - Today

NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad

A government aided institution affiliated to APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University, Kerala

Assistant Professor | Department of Computer Science and Engineering

06/02/2006-21/01/2022

NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad

- Geometric Deep Learning
- Social Network Mining
- Big Data Analytics

Refereed Journal Publications

- Anuraj Mohan, Karthika P V, Parvathi Sankar and Maya Manohar K (2022), Improving anti-money laundering in bitcoin using evolving graph convolutions and deep neural decision forest, *Data Technologies and Applications (SCIE)*, *Emerald* Vol 57, pp. 313-329. https://doi.org/10.1108/DTA-06-2021-0167
- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2022), Representation learning for temporal networks using temporal random walk and deep autoencoder, *Discrete Applied Mathematics (SCIE)*, *Elsevier* Vol 319, pp 595-605.

https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dam.2022.01.017

- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2021), Temporal network embedding using graph attention network, *Complex and Intelligent Systems (SCIE), Springer*.Vol 9, pp. 13-27. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40747-021-00332-x
- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2020), Link prediction in dynamic networks using time-aware network embedding and time series forecasting, *Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing(SCIE), Springer*, Vol 12, pp. 1981–1993. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12652-020-02289-0
- Anuraj Mohan and K. V. Pramod (2019), Network representation learning: models, methods and applications, SN Applied Sciences(ESCI), Springer, Vol 1, pp. 1-23. https://doi.org/10.1007/s42452-019-1044-9
- Anuraj Mohan, R Venkatesan and K. V. Pramod (2017), A scalable method for link prediction in large real world networks, *Journal of Parallel and Distributed Computing(SCIE)*, Elsevier, Vol 109, pp. 89-101. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpdc.2017.05.009

Contact

- Sarangi
 Akathethara, Palakkad 678008
- □ +91 9496353749
- anurajmohan@gmail.com
- anurajmohan@nssce.ac.in
- Nisha C C and Anuraj Mohan (2018), A social recommender system using deep architecture and network embedding, Applied Intelligence(SCIE), Springer, Vol 49, pp. 1937-1953.https://doi.org/10.1007/s10489-018-1359-z
- Aswathy Divakaran and Anuraj Mohan (2019), Temporal Link Prediction: A Survey, New Generation Computing (SCIE), Springer, Vol 38, pp. 213 - 258. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00354-019-00065-z

SKills

Python, Scikit-Learn, NetworkX, Keras, Pytorch, Hadoop, Spark, SQL

Subject Expertise

Theory of Computation, Data Structures, Operating Systems, Python Programming, Database Systems, Machine Learning, Information Retrieval.

Recent Activities

- Reviewer for IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence
- Reviewer for IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems
- Invited Talk on 'Machine Learning Algorithms Theory and Practice' for Faculty Development Programme on Machine Learning and Cybersecurity at KMCT college of Engineering, Calicut
- Reviewer for ACM Computing Surveys
- Invited Talk on 'Deep Learning on Graphs' for Faculty Development Programme on Artificial Intelligence and Data Science at Royal College of Engineering and Technology, Thrissur
- Reviewer for IEEE Transactions on Computational Social Systems
- Reviewer for CAAI Transactions on Intelligence Technology, Wiley
- Reviewer for New Generation Computing, Springer
- Reviewer for iScience, Cell Press
- Reviewer for Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing, Springer
- Invited Talk on 'Network Embedding' for National Workshop on Graphs Complex Networks at CUSAT, Cochin

Web Links

- Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=PwHP6YoAAAAJhI=en
- ORCHID : https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1044-9368
- ResearchGate: https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Anuraj-Mohan-2
- Webpage : https://anurajmohan.in/

Palakkad, 11th July 2024

Anuraj Mohan